rachelheldevans.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy

_Updated July 26, 2016_

 **This site is for adults, age 18 and older.**

 **What you say may be used by Rachel in books and blog posts.**  
By using this site, and/or contacting Rachel you hereby understand and give Rachel license to use without limitation any of your submitted messages, emails or comments in future works created by Rachel including but not limited to future books and blog posts.

 **We understand that your privacy is important.**  
Your use of this site constitutes that you understand and accept this privacy policy.

 **Information collected**  
We collect information about the use of this site such as visits, clicks and IP addresses. We use this information for statistical, informational and community quality control purposes.

We use cookies on your device to collect information, including Google Analytics Advertising Features such as:

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting
  * Integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers

[Learn how to opt-out of Google Analytics information collection](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

 **Settings and Preference Cookies**  
This site may store and retrieve non-personal information on your computer in the form of cookies. This information is used to customize your experience while visiting the site.

 **Information submitted**  
Any personally identifying information you submit to this site including but not limited to: feedback, comments or email messages may be used to contact you.

 **Comment Ownership and Information Submitted with Comments**  
Any comment submitted is owned by the person who submitted the comment. Any liability for a comment is the responsibility of the person who submitted the comment. By submitting a comment to this site you allow us any rights needed to display and edit your comment.  _ **We may remove any comment from this site for any reason at our discretion without notice.  **_Any information submitted with comments may be sent to the third party commenting platform [Disqus](http://disqus.com/) for the purpose of identifying and displaying comments on this site in accordance with the Disqus terms of service and privacy policy. Disqus is a third party service provider that is not owned or operated by us. Disqus gives comment creators and website creators control over comments created and displayed. You may read more about the Disqus [privacy policies here](http://disqus.com/privacy-policy/) and [terms of service here](http://disqus.com/terms-of-service/).

 **Third Party Advertising**  
We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website or read our RSS feeds. These companies may use information ( **not**  including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here (http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

 **Changes to this policy**

This privacy policy may be updated from time to time. The updates and changes will be posted to the privacy policy page on this website located at <http://rachelheldevans.com/privacy>.
